# **ERIK WAIBEL**

#### SENIOR FRONTEND ENGINEER

As a passionate and self-motivated lead JavaScript engineer, I have 5+ years experience in creating production-ready web applications, with a focus on the latest frontend technologies. I increased EBIT by 30% while leading a team of 15+ software developers to a successful global production release for General Motors European brand sites. I helped reduce our team's development time by 20% with implementation of Git flow methodology and best practices. I have strong communication skills and can thrive under any high pressure environment.

ejwaibel+resume@gmail.com
#1 480-331-1899

https://www.github.com/ejwaibelhttps://www.linkedin.com/in/ejwaibel

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Lead Frontend Engineer | Vue Developer

iRELO

04/2018 - Present

Principal frontend engineer/architect responsible for building and maintaining 10 single page web applications utilizing latest frontend technology stacks. Design & develop Vue.js components to integrate with new and existing applications across the organization.

- Tune and maximize performance of web applications in order to reduce page load time by 30%, while continuing to learn new patterns and best practices
- Utilized Webpack build integration to perform JavaScript compilation and minification for all frontend development, which reduced final asset sizes by 80%
- Interface with design team and ensure provided assets and layout will conform with best practices for responsive & mobile first
- Coordinate with PM in Asana utilizing an agile process to ensure all bugs & features are completed on time
- Developed custom eslint and stylelint configurations for inclusion with all company projects
- Organized Git standardization and process through Gitlab, while training and supporting developers
- Produced Git CLI script to generate automatic changelog and Gitlab release
- Integrated latest JavaScript standards and ES2017 features

# **Adjunct Faculty**

Chandler Gilbert Community College

01/2018 - Present

Develop and teach 3 courses as an adjunct faculty in the Computer Information Systems department with a focus on web development integrating HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript.

#### **SKILLS**

Expert							
HTML5 CSS3 JavaScrip	JavaScript						
jQuery SCSS/LESS/PostCSS Git							
NodeJS REST ES6/ES2017	7						
Grunt Gulp Perl SDL0	SDLC						
Agile Method SCM Linux	X						
Intermediate							

Intermediate							
shell		Vue.js			Nuxt		
Web Components				Angular			
Webpack				Express			
Unit Tests (Jasmine)							
E2E Tests (Cypress)					PHP		
Mongo	В	MySQL	-	M	1SSQL		
Oracle	Phot	toshop	SE	0	AEM		
WordPre	ess						

# DevOps Docker AWS Jenkins Java

#### Lead JavaScript Engineer | Senior Web Developer

General Motors IT - Global Brands

07/2014 - 04/2018

Started as an individual contributor migrating 3rd party web applications into GM ecosystem. Promoted to Principal UI Engineer responsible for end to end feature enablement across the UI layer, and the integration of UI into the broader ecosystem of General Motors brand websites. Increased EBIT by 30% while leading a team of 15+ software developers to a successful global production release for General Motors European brand sites.

- Lead team of 15+ developers to deliver 65 custom AEM components for the European brands release, which reached 20 different countries
- Implemented solution for functional website integration of social media, Google analytics, and SEO within AEM infrastructure
- Analyzed performance of brand sites and executed plan to increase initial page load time by 30% and decrease asset sizes by 25%
- Applied CSS3 styles to modular components based on PSD styleguides
- Produced multiple angular applications for inclusion into a Bootstrap/Foundation framework
- Designed solution for custom SCSS inheritance to accomodate multiple shared projects
- Designed solution for internal Gulp build process and provided enhancements based on project challenges, which helped decrease build time by 2 hours
- Triaged bugs on a daily basis to ensure issues are resolved in time for production release
- Coordinated with business and design teams to ensure proper requirements for new features
- Researched advanced CSS & JavaScript techniques to implement latest browser features and enhance the customer's experience
- Performed Subversion and Git operations within a development and production environment

# Software Engineer II

iTRACS / Commscope

09/2012 - 07/2014

Individual contributor responsible for the developing and maintaining an enterprise level responsive single-page web application, supported on al major browsers, providing business critical datacenter management solution. I was also given a project and assigned as the lead developer for design and implementation of a customer API portal with multiple WordPress instances. I cooperatively worked closely with team members in an agile environment to ensure implementation of features/functionality conform to release/business objectives.

- Created and deployed 10+ advanced RESTful API interfaces with PHP and SOAP Web Services, which had to support internal and external API requests
- Performed Subversion and Git operations within a development and production environment
- Managed product enhancements and defects in a time-senstitive and high pressure agile development process with monthly production releases
- Coordinated with QA to release the initial version of customer-facing single-page web application on time with a team of 3 web developers and 2 web designers.

# **Adjunct Faculty**

Art Institute of Phoenix

09/2010 - 12/2014

Developed and taught 8 courses as an adjunct faculty in the Graphic & Web Design department, with average class size of 12 students.

## Owner | IT Engineer | Software Developer

Everything Just Works, LLC

05/2010 - 10/2013

- As an Owner and for Everything Just Works, LLC I wanted to empower individuals to use the computer to its full potential and be aware of the problems that can arise so that they aren't stuck paying someone to recover their data. I also eradicated viruses and malware from infected computers after performing necessary troubleshooting techniques.
- In my Software Developer role I consulted with 5 clients to develop custom WordPress integrations. I was also contracted with a long-term project for building a custom web application for a Realty Company that would allow users to search for houses based on a given MLS listing. The tools used for this project were: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Object Oriented PHP5 (no framework), IIS 7.5, MSSQL 2008, Google Maps API

#### Software Developer

Insight Global, Contract w/Level 3 Communications

07/2012 - 10/2012

As a Software Developer contractor I was tasked to design & develop an internal website for network planners that was built on top of an Apache server with HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, and CSS3. I was also in charge of configuring and administering the Bugzilla installation on Linux CentOS server for the customer required bug tracking system. I developed internal Perl modules for enhancing database connections, combining common utility functions, and extracting Excel spreadsheet customizations.

#### Systems Engineer

APEX Systems, Contract w/Wells Fargo

10/2011 - 06/2012

As a Systems Engineer contractor, I was assigned the development of 15 customized in-house Perl modules for automating highly critical financial processes. I extended Perl scripts to support automation tasks across 15 UNIX Solaris and Linux servers, including threads that would run commands on specified servers in parallel. Provided multi-level support to the Customer Care team, located worldwide, and employees that worked directly with Wells Fargo Wholesale customers.

#### Software Developer | SCM Consultant

A Better Solution, Inc.

04/2007 - 06/2011

Working as an SCM Consultant I integrated the tools developed by A Better Solution with existing ClearCase configurations to produce automated SCM processes and procedures. I implemented over 100 Perl scripts and applications to support developers integration with ClearCase, ensured project builds and releases performed efficiently and correctly through the use of IBM Rational BuildForge, produced automated build scripts using Perl and shell programming, and provided first level technical assistance to end users including, but not limited to: replicating errors, resolving application issues, and investigating errors.

## Jr. PHP Developer

BlueHornet.com

09/2006 - 04/2007

As a junior PHP developer, I enhanced the existing client email web application with custom Object Oriented code for quicker development and easier maintainability. Coordinated with the graphic design team and integrated Photoshop layouts using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS. Documented new features thoroughly for use with customer support documentation.

## **EDUCATION**

# B.S., Computer Science

California State Polytechnic University

09/2001 - 08/2006